🎙️ EduLens AI — Refined Demo
Part 1: The Hook — Most EdTech today has a 'Shallow Learning' problem. We built an Explain-First platform that decodes a student's mental model.
Part 2: The "Explain-First" Challenge — Student view. Instead of multiple-choice, the student explains Photosynthesis in their own words.
Student types: "Plants use sunlight to make oxygen so that humans and animals can breathe." The AI will evaluate this explanation.
AI feedback: Identifies this as Incomplete Understanding. Notes the student focused on oxygen and missed glucose/energy production. Bloom's level: Remembering.
Part 3: Mastery Tools — Navigate the Knowledge Graph. Each interaction updates the graph and shows mastered concepts and prerequisites.
Open the EduLens Assistant (Chatbot). It uses Socratic prompts to help students bridge gaps without giving answers away.
Part 4: The Live Classroom — Educator Dashboard. Teachers see aggregated Misconception Heatmaps and can click "Go Live" for a real-time feed using WebSockets.
Intervention Queue flags struggling students so teachers can step in immediately.
Conclusion: EduLens AI understands students, not just scores. Thanks for watching.